Guide to Non-Commercial Disc Collections ARS.0033
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 1. program and series titles, A-Z, 6824 discs
  - Salvation Army, 1956; 1 16" vinyl disc
  - Salvation Army. Reflections By Starlight, 1961; 2 16" vinyl discs
  - San Francisco Sketchbook, 1951-1952; 5 16" instantaneous discs
  - Saturday Night Serenade, 1949-06-28; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Say It With Music, 1946-1943; 2 discs
  - Schaeffer Parade, The, 1948-08-15; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Secret Agent, 1941-03; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Serenade For Strings, 1946-09-07; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - SESAC Transcriptions Library Service, 59 16" vinyl discs
  - Shady Valley Folks, 1947-12; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Sherlock Holmes, 1942-02-08; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Showtime, U.S.A., 1950-12-18; 1 12" instantaneous disc
  - Sincerely, Kenny Baker, 1945-1946; 2 16" vinyl discs
  - Sing Along With Mitch, 1961-1965; 14 instantaneous discs
  - Smile Time, 1947-05-05; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Spirit Of The Vikings, The, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - Stage Door Canteen, 1942, 1946; 2 instantaneous discs
  - Stairway To The Stars, 1949-05-15; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Standard Hour, 1938-1955; 611 discs
    Accompanying paper materials
    Cue sheets/scripts, album covers and programs (including bound volumes containing 1932-1955 programs) are available for this series.
  - Standard Program Library, 298 16" vinyl discs
  - Standard School Broadcast, 1935-1969; 953 discs
    Cue sheets/scripts, album covers and programs (including bound volumes containing 1928-1965 programs) are available for this series.
  - Star Spangled Vaudeville, 1942; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Starlight Operetta, 1950-07-30; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Stars For Defense, 1957-1962; 6 vinyl discs
  - Stradivari Program, 1946; 6 16" instantaneous discs
  - Straight Arrow, 1948-05; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Streamlined Fairy Tales, 1947; 1 16" vinyl disc
  - Summer Electric Hour, 1948-06-06; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Sunrise Salute, 1949; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Sunset Serenade, 1950-04-05; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Symphonies of the Sage (Sons Of The Pioneers), 14 16" vinyl discs
  - Synagogue, 12 16" vinyl discs
  - Tapestries of Life, 1951; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Tennessee Ernie Show, 5 16" vinyl discs
  - Thesaurus (RCA, NBC), 15 16" vinyl discs
  - This I Believe, 1 12" vinyl discs
  - This Is America, 1941; 4 16" instantaneous discs
  - This, Our America, 1939-06-04; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Through The Looking Glass, 1950-04-15; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Tide Show, The, 1952-09-01; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Time To Smile, 1941-12; 1 10" instantaneous disc
  - Titan Library Service, 1 12" shellac disc
  - Transatlantic Call, 23 16" vinyl discs
  - Treasure Hour Of Song, 1946-06; 3 16" instantaneous discs
  - Treasury Department, 81 discs
    - Treasury Department, 9 discs
    - Eddy Arnold, 2 16" vinyl discs
    - Guest Star, 1947-1962; 38 16" vinyl discs
    - Take Stock In America, 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Treasury Song Parade, 25 16" vinyl discs
    - Voices Of The Farm, 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Voices Of The People, 1942-1943; 6 16" vinyl discs
    - Minute Man, 1943-02-01; 1 16" vinyl disc
  - True or False, 1949; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Twenty Questions, 1947-1948; 4 16" instantaneous discs
  - U.S. Air Force, 184 vinyl discs
    - U.S. Air Force, 2 vinyl discs
    - U.S. Air Force Reserve. Reserved For You, 1956-1962; 28 vinyl discs
    - U.S. Air Force Reserve. Soundflights Into Jazz, 4 12" vinyl discs
    - Country Music Time, 48 12" vinyl discs
    - Flight Through Life, 1 12" vinyl disc
    - Manhattan Melodies, 13 12" vinyl discs
    - Music in the Air, 2 7" vinyl discs
    - Serenade In Blue, 86 vinyl discs
  - U.S. Armed Forces Institute, 3 12" vinyl discs
  - U.S. Army, 66 vinyl discs
    - U.S. Army, 5 12" vinyl discs
    - Army Bandstand, 19 vinyl discs
    - Country Style, USA, 16 12" vinyl discs
    - Forward March, 1956; 5 16" vinyl discs
    - Gene Price Country Express, 1974; 2 12" vinyl discs
    - March Music, 2 16" vinyl discs
    - National Anthems, 2 12" vinyl discs
    - Proudly We Hail, 1956; 13 16" vinyl discs
    - Stars On Parade, 1950; 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Voice Of The Army, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - U.S. Department Of Labor, 1 12" vinyl disc
  - U.S. Department Of The Interior Fish And Wildlife Service, Bureau Of Commercial Fisheries, 1 12" vinyl disc
  - U.S. Marine Corps, 26 vinyl discs
    - U.S. Marine Corps, 6 vinyl discs
    - It's The Tops, 3 16" vinyl discs
    - Jazz On The Potomac, 7 12" vinyl discs
    - Jerry Gray Show, 3 16" vinyl discs
    - Les Brown Show, 5 16" vinyl discs
    - Take Five, 1 12" vinyl disc
    - Toni Arden Show, 1954; 1 16" vinyl disc
  - U.S. Navy, 70 discs
    - U.S. Navy, 17 vinyl discs
    - Broadway In Review, 1954; 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Join The Navy, 1956; 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Land's Best Bands, 1951; 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Music On Deck. Lawrence Welk, 1959-1960; 28 vinyl discs
    - Music On Deck. Pat Boone, 8 vinyl discs
    - Navy Band Showcase, 1 12" vinyl disc
    - Navy Hour, 1945-07-10; 1 16" instantaneous disc
    - Navy Swings, The, 4 16" vinyl discs
    - Portraits in Patriotism, 1 12" vinyl disc
    - Teacher, The, 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Travel The World In Song, 1 12" vinyl disc
    - What In The World Happened?, 1976; 2 12" vinyl discs
    - Your Navy Show, 1954; 2 16" vinyl discs
    - Your Star Time, 1953; 1 16" vinyl disc
  - U.S. Office of Civilian Defense, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - U.S. Office of Civilian Defense. Yankee Doodle, 3 16" vinyl discs
  - U.S. Post Office Department, 1967; 1 10" vinyl disc
  - United Nations, 64 discs
    - United Nations, 12 discs
    - Celebration Of The First Anniversary of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1949-12-10; 8 16" vinyl discs
    - Commemoration Of The Second Anniversary of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1950-12-10; 5 16" vinyl discs
    - Document A/777, 2 16" vinyl discs
    - Eleven Memory Street, 3 16" vinyl discs
    - Memo From Lake Success, 1 16" vinyl disc
    - Shooting Gallery, 4 16" vinyl discs
    - Tomorrow For Two, 2 16" vinyl discs
    - U.N. Story, 1 10" vinyl disc
    - U.N. Birthday Story, The, 1949-10-24; 1 16" instantaneous disc
    - UNESCO. Energy In The Service Of Man, 2 12" instantaneous discs
    - UNESCO. Backdoor Travelogue, 1 12" instantaneous disc
    - UNESCO. Canticle of Hope, 2 16" instantaneous discs
    - UNICEF. Billy Hits the Jackpot, 1958; 1 10" vinyl disc
    - UNICEF. Meanest Man In Town, The, 1 10" vinyl disc
    - UNICEF. Trial of Sergeant Bill, The, 1957; 1 10" vinyl disc
    - United Nations Story, The, 13 16" vinyl discs
    - United Nations Today, The, 1950; 2 16" instantaneous discs
    - Your Seat at the Table, 1955; 1 10" vinyl disc
  - United Service Organizations, 1961; 1 12" vinyl disc
  - United States Information Service, 1949; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - United States Steel Hour, The, 1949-1952; 11 16" instantaneous disc
  - Unlimited Horizons, 1941-04-22; 6 12" instantaneous discs
  - Veterans Administration, 1949; 1 16" vinyl disc
  - Veterans Administration. Here's To Veterans, 34 vinyl discs
  - Veterans' Theater Of The Air, 1948-05; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Voice Of America, 20 16" vinyl discs
  - Voice Of America. Fun With Music, 5 16" vinyl discs
  - Voice Of America. Musica De Siempre, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - Voice Of Firestone, The, 1936-1956; 22 discs
  - War Department, 34 12" vinyl discs
  - Warriors Of Peace, 1947; 6 16" vinyl discs
  - We The People, 3 instantaneous discs
  - Wealth Of The West, 1941; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - Western Hit Revue, 1949-04-28; 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Westertype, 1 16" instantaneous disc
  - Westinghouse Adventures In Research, 12 16" vinyl discs
  - Witch's Tale, 1 16" shellac disc
  - Works Progress Administration, 1936-1942; 339 discs
  - World Feature. Jam Session, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - World Feature. Sing, America, Sing, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - World Program Service, 34 16" vinyl discs
  - World's Best Seller, The, 1 16" vinyl disc
  - Yesterday Brings You Tomorrow, 1 16" shellac disc
  - You And Gadgets, 1949; 2 16" instantaneous discs
  - You And Your America, 1940-05-19; 3 12" instantaneous discs
  - You Bet Your Life, 1 10" instantaneous discs
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 3 10" vinyl discs
  - Your Hit Parade, 1935-1952; 18 instantaneous discs
  - Zane Grey Show, 1947-12; 1 16" instantaneous disc
- 2. general content types
  For the most part, content types have been identified for genres other than music. Quantities are estimated.
  - advertisements, 100 discs
  - advertisements (political), 10 discs
  - amateur recordings, 105 discs
    Label information suggests relatively informal speech, singing and playing by family or friends.
  - custom/vanity pressings, 57 discs
    Studio and pressing plant information has been recorded when present. Please note that the general ARS record library also contains many custom and privately-printed recordings.
  - motion picture-related, 98 discs
    Includes soundtracks, production discs (largely from MGM 1940s musicals), promotional recordings and advertisements.
  - news and speech, 456 discs
    News, commentary, panel discussion, speeches, lectures, sportscasting, etc. Most are from or for the radio.
  - dubbed copies, 157 discs
    Some identified as dubs may not be issued takes, and there are probably other dubs not identified as such. Many appear to be party records (i.e. risque songs not otherwise easily available in record stores).
  - ethnographic and field recordings, 64 discs
    - African Music Research discs from Johannesburg, South Africa, 6 16" instantaneous discs
    - Aboriginal Music From the Northern Territory of Australia (Australian Broadcasting Commission, Processed By Columbia Graphophone), 1948; 11 12" vinyl discs
    - Cook Island Songs Recorded For The South Seas Commission (Columbia Graphophone (Aust.) Pty. Ltd.), 2 12" vinyl discs
    - Finnie Collection recordings from Lebanon, Venezula, Korea and elsewhere for use in Bechtel films, 1951-1956; 15 instantaneous discs
    - Folk Songs and Dances From The Pacific, Recorded by Fred Drilhon (Australian Broadcasting Commission, processed By Columbia Graphophone), 1954; 3 12" vinyl discs
    - Linnell Migratory Camp, Visalia, California. A. Carl Killion - Turkish Lady B. Evelyn Pennington - Old Grumbler, 1945-12-27; 1 16" instantaneous disc
      This unusual 16" cardboard-based lacquer was recorded by Nadean Hart in 1945. This recording has been deposited at the Library Of Congress American Folklife Center as part of AFS 9434-9447: Nadean Hart Collection of Folk Songs and Ballads. It is unclear what relationship this disc has to the AFS collection. It is probably a contemporary dub.
    - New Guinea and Papuan Native Music (Australian Broadcasting Commission, processed By Columbia Graphophone), 1950; 6 12" vinyl discs
    - Pueblo Indian songs, 1945-01-14; 2 12" instantaneous discs
      Two glass-based discs recorded by Albuquerque Radio and Appliance featuring Mike Reyna, Paul Toya and Heinrich Shultz singing traditonal Taos Pueblo songs as well as popular material (such as "Bomb the Berlin"). These discs were originally owned by Virgil Whitaker, a Stanford alumnus and professor emeritus who worked in the Indian Education Service in New Mexico during WWII. However, the original recordings were made by anthropologists Florence Hawley Ellis and Donovan Senter, and these are probably copies made at the time. For more information refer to the Florence Hawley Ellis and Donovan Senter Collection of Hispanic, Isleta, and Laguna Songs at the University of New Mexico Center for Southwest Research.
    - Sam Kapa, J. Louis Hila, Donald Parshon, Cazimero. Kaikoo; Lihiwai [photocopy of lyrics in Hawaiian enclosed], 1 10" instantaneous disc
    - Sanscrit Chant, Sri-Sulul (Aladdin Recording, Portland, Oregon), 1 10" instantaneous disc
    - Sarat Lahiri and Todi, Sitar, Tabla and Banya, 341 West 58th St. New York City - Raga Behag; Hindu Love Song [handwritten label], 1 10" shellac disc
    - Sydney University Expedition 1949. Chants And Rituals Recorded By Professor Elkin (Australian Record Company), 12 16" vinyl discs
  - public service announcements and programs, 69 discs
  - visually unidentifiable, 372 discs
- 3. major orchestras represented
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, Boston Pops, 90 discs
  - CBS Symphony Orchestra, 43 discs
  - Hollywood Bowl, 538 discs
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic, 150 discs
  - NBC Symphony Orchestra, 241 discs
  - New York Philharmonic, 112 discs
  - Philadelphia Orchestra, 24 discs
  - San Francisco Symphony Orchestra and Opera, 147 discs
- 4. Stanford University recordings, 178 discs
  Not all Stanford-related discs have been identified, and some recordings donated by faculty and alumni have no relation to Stanford. The collection contains donations from Sandor Salgo, Herbert Nanney, Leonard Ratner, Harold Schmidt, Jan Popper and many others. Many transcriptions were once part of KZSU's library. While most discs are of various baccalaureates, commencements, and other addresses, a few highlights are as follows:
  David Starr Jordan's "The Stanford Spirit" on a 1916 custom shellac pressing; an interview with Mrs. David Starr Jordan in 1951; Richard Lyman home recordings from the early 1930s; Stanford Women's Glee Club 1937; Stanford Symphony Orchestra conducted by Sandor Salgo and Leonard Ratner; original recordings of the Stanford Scalp Song from composer Irving Bibo; Stanford Players productions from the late 1940s; Ray Lyman Wilbur and D.B. Tressider at an Alumni Banquet in 1943; Yvor Winters readings; Wallace Stegner singing the song "Sam Hall"; Herbert Nanney playing the organ at Memorial; a Putnam Aldrich harpsichord recital from 1953; Stanford Big Game Gaieties from 1940.
  Other Stanford-related collections at the Archive of Recorded Sound include the Stanford Recital Collection (ARS0021), Stanford Tape Collection (ARS0112), Stanford Speech Collection (ARS0022), Meyer Library Lecture Tapes (ARS0116), Preservation Master Tape Collection (ARS0097), Stanford Program for Recordings in Sound Collection (ARS0104), Roy A. Long Collection (ARS0086), KZSU collection (ARS0062), Stanford Marching Band Collection (ARS0089), and the Harold Schmidt Collection (ARS0120).
- 5. notable donations
  By no means is this an exhaustive list. Many of the donors below also have their own collections, and links are provided to their finding aids.
  - Arnold, Bob, 16 instantaneous discs
    Related Archival Materials
    See also the Bob Arnold Collection (ARS0080).
    Arnold was a collector and researcher in Berkeley, California. Some or all discs are from Jaxyson Radio Service in Oakland, a studio which was known for a few blues and gospel pressings, as well as many instantaneous recordings (many of which were compiled on a commercial CD set titled The Jaxyson Records Story).
  - Blackmar, Lois, 1934-1950; 6 12" instantaneous discs
    Six discs compiling rare recordings by singer Joseph Bentonelli.
  - Block, Al, 1937-1971; 275 discs
    See also the Al Block Broadcast Collection (ARS0077).
    Block was a collector and long-time friend of the Archive. Most of these discs were from the last of his many donations. While his interest was mainly in classical, one may also find dramatic performances, popular music and even a country and western program (the Sons Of The Pioneers' Symphonies of the Sage).
  - Bonelli, Mona Modini, 1949-04-17; 4 discs
    See also Box 34, Tape 26 in the Richard Bonelli Collection (ARS0005).
    Richard Bonelli with Fern Sayre, soprano, G. Alexander Schriener, organ, Mormon Tabernacle Choir. Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Deutsches Requiem.
  - Borisoff, Alexander (via Janice Ortega), 1945-1949; 15 12" instantaneous discs
    Discs originally owned by cellist and composer Alexander Borisoff and donated by his grandaughter Janice Ortega. Includes a complete Your Hit Parade (Lucky Strike) program on NBC/KFI from 9/14/1935 and a 1949 private recording of Borisoff's Poeme Ancient by the Hollywood Symphony Orchestra conducted by Victor Young with Borisoff playing cello and narration by Edward G. Robinson.
  - Brown, Nate, 1935-1949; 210 discs
    See also the Nate Brown Western Sound Archive Collection (ARS0124) and the Ed Wilkinson Collection (ARS0092).
    The Western Sound Archive, run by collector and trader Nate Brown along with fellow collector Ed Wilkinson, was a non-profit service that distributed rare classical recordings on open reel tape. These discs were the original sources for much of this privately circulated material.
  - Davis, Hugh, 65 instantaneous discs
    Exact provenance is unclear; discs may have been donated by an intermediary. Davis was a jazz fan and recording engineer originally from Wichita, Kansas who worked as an electrical engineer and for the Seeburg jukebox company. An associate of John Steiner, they ran the S.D. (Steiner-Davis) and Paramount reissue labels together, and recorded traditional jazz performances both live and from radio broadcasts in the Chicago area. Most of these discs have minimal annotations, and some may be dubs or tests of commercial issues. Notable recordings include: Sunday Swing Concert, Sherman Hotel in Chicago 11/3/1940; Teddy Wilson, Duffy's Tavern 4/7/1942; Bob Crosby, Jess Stacy, Fitch Bandwagon 5/24/42; George Barnes, Roy Shields Program WMAQ 5/21/42; Bill Davison - Blatz Palm Gardens 5/30/41; and various recordings of Mel Henke, Don Ewell, Billy Maxted, Floyd Bean, and others.
  - Drob, Harold, 85 instantaneous discs
    Drob was a jazz record collector and researcher devoted to trumpeter Bunk Johnson. Many of these discs are dubs from rare jazz 78s, but others may be unique recordings. The Boris Blinder records are probably not part of this donation.
  - Elwood, Phil, 16 discs
    A few discs from the collection of famed San Francisco music critic and radio producer Phil Elwood. Most discs are unidentified, but there are two of Bill Russell Introducing and playing with Bunk Johnson and an undated Kid Ory aircheck.
  - Fagan, Ted, 20 instantaneous discs
    See also the discs in the Ted Fagan Collection (ARS0008).
  - Finnie, Anne Ackerman, 1941-1956; 63 instantaneous discs
    See also the Richard Finnie Collection (ARS0117).
    Discs from Richard Sterling Finnie, donated by his widow. Finnie was a writer and producer who worked for Bechtel and traveled around the world making recordings for use in promotional films. He was also an enthusiastic home-recorder, with many hours of radio broadcasts in his collection. Most of the discs here are 1940s airchecks of popular music from WEAF, WABC, WNEW, and other stations, but there are also original field recordings of ethnic music from Lebanon, Venezula, Korea, and Trinidad, and folk music by Massachusetts pipline worker P.G. Spike Downes (mosty of which are also exist as tape transfers in the Finnie Collection).
  - Jacobsen, Arnold, 1935-1959; 435 discs
    See also the Arnold Jacobsen Collection (ARS0122).
    Arnold Jacobsen was a record collector and dealer with a specialization in popular music of the early-to-mid 20th century. The discs here reflect that broadness, and include many airchecks and transcriptions. There are also discs of Jacobsen's radio program The Memory Shop (named for his record store), audio letters he made while in the army, and several location recordings of temple services.
  - Kapfenberg, Eleanor, 1944-1962; 254 discs
    Kapfenberg's donation largely consists of pressed transcriptions, but there are also several location recordings of San Francisco Bay Area dance bands, such as John Wolohan Orchestra at the El Patio Ballroom in 1946-47 and the Jack Fina Orchestra at the Claremont Hotel in 1946. Most discs are in very poor condition.
  - Layer, Harold, 187 discs
    Hal Layer is Professor Emeritus at San Francisco State University and a man of diverse interests (http://userwww.sfsu.edu/~hl/). His collection here includes CBS Symphony, NBC Symphony, and New York Philharmonic airchecks, WBBM broadcasts, Nat King Cole's Wildroot Cream Oil program, and many pressed transcriptions.
  - Lund, Jack, 19 instantaneous discs
    See also the Jack Lund Collection (ARS0045)
    Most discs are a performance of Otello by the NBC Symphony Orchestra under Toscanini 12/6-13/1947.
  - Malloch, William (via Bill Doggett), 53 instantaneous discs
    Malloch was music director at KPFK, artistic director of the Ojai Music Festival, and a music teacher at UCLA. All discs from his collection are instantaneous-cut, and contain rare recordings of the NBC Symphony, New York Philharmonic, Cleveland Symphony, San Francisco Symphony, and other orchestral performances.
  - Moran, William R., 1936-1953; 20 instantaneous discs
    See also William R. Moran Sound Recording Collection (ARS0075).
    William Moran was a collector, researcher, writer, and discographer, particularly in the field of early sound recordings and vocal art music. Moran was one of the founders of the Archive of Recorded Sound, and he donated thousands of rare recordings and ephemera to the Archive until he passed away in 2004.
  - Quilter, Thomas J., 1935-1961; 193 discs
    One of the largest single donations of transcriptions and instantaneous discs to the Archive. Among the many offerings: Standard Hour and Standard School Broadcasts; AFRS discs stamped U.S.S. Antietam and Oneida; Royal Hawaiian Minstrels on Stichting Radio Omroep [Netherlands] in 1949; several San Francisco Sketchbook programs on ABC 1951-1952; many Masterworks From France programs; a KGO program on Socialism.
  - Rhines, Howard, 1935-1952; 41 discs
    See also the Howard Rhines Collection (ARS0102).
    Howard Rhines was a composer, announcer and program director at Los Angeles classical radio station KFAC.
  - Schmidt, Harold, 1948; 15 16" instantaneous discs
    This collection contains only 16" discs from Schmidt. Smaller-sized discs remain in the Harold Schmidt Collection (ARS0120).
    Schmidt was choral director and a professor of music at Stanford. These discs are primarily two sets of the Stanford Players' performance of Britten's Peter Grimes, May 27-29, 1948.
  - Schwabacher, Cynthia, 1940-1953; 109 instantaneous discs
    See also the James Schwabacher Collection (ARS0024).
    Cynthia is the sister of singer and voice teacher James Schwabacher, and although the James Schwabacher Collection also contains lacquers, it would seem that their collections have been mixed to a certain degree. Nevertheless, the discs included here are probably all from Cynthia, and offer a remarkable snapshot of 1940s radio, including news, sports, comedy, and political programming.
  - Waggener, Hewitt (via Richard Gould), 1935-1965; 1524 instantaneous discs
    Waggener was a saxophonist who ran a professional recording studio in Southern California, but spent much of his free time perfecting his home recording system. Almost all of these discs are air checks, most from stations KFI, KFAC, KFWB, and KCBH. Some of are from television programs. Waggener meticulously logged his recording setup on disc sleeves, but usually only wrote a few notes about what was being recorded. Many appear to be broadcasts of transcriptions or pre-recorded music, but there are undoubtedly many undiscovered and unique recordings in a donation of this magnitude.